23 years of service and started working for the city right after that on February 13, 2006. His wife Gloria has put up with him from his 30-year anniversary!
They have a thirty year old son Dartainian who is Dr in Brooklyn New York
And at 26th year older Jamie he was teacher in Oklahoma City & it's currently finishing upper second masters program
And Michelle Soccoch is a middle school soccer team. Randy has worked for the city, ten years in plans on retiring and On August 1st
Randy's big helpin our office he was wonderful to have I don't know what i'm gonna do with that so
Appreciate all of it work that you does & The Work He Does For This City
So Randy what are you gonna do in your retirement?
Thank You for Your Services Sound Like, Kids Are A lot Smarter Than You
Okay I Jen and through is Population for Miami's 125th Anniversary Celebration
The Council Approval For the Population that we're issuing, We have a much different proof
Second second.
Western?
Something?
I don't know.
On schedule personal period is in my audience it was you to address the council
Item five, Consentant Jen and Staff is recommending item 639 if there are no questions
Second
Second.
Second, I'm Tann Resolution Revening the Central Avenue Bridge
The Adelaide Central Attony bridge in city and iam a Ottawa County Oklahoma
Joe thank You sir they are our tribal local home with assistance from
The Bureau of Indian Fathers, Eastern Oklahoma Region
Secured funding from how we trust fund is the IRB program that helped us to help
We'd like recognize a tribe for their donation and
To our appreciation by renaming in bridge
The Ottawa Central Avenue Bridge and placing it back on there noting such
Joe the Adelaide, D.A., W E as the Native American Pronunciation for AtoWI sir
Let me just say we appreciate a lot of the tribes contributions
When I first started that project
The budget was 6,700 thousand in for various reasons it continued to grow
And when the tribes stepped forward and they would come up with a big $1 million
For that project is let us take what has been just an ordinary bridge
It makes really nice structure out of
And say the taxpayers 7.7000 dollars
So I'm so very much appreciate you
And this will be the market going on in bridge
We'll need to prove that plaque some spelling and things
Yes, it's real close
What is also very important here honor of the plaque
Because we want make sure
That when we have elected officials
When there was project as you can see
Recognizing both Canton Brantles mayors
Then councilman passed in present
That we have on there if somebody else that you are missing
If he could let us know right away
Because this is going to be something
We'll need a posterity
Okay, so
Resolutionary naming the bridge
Most new improvement
Second
Johnson
Hi
I'm 11 G.H., 2Task over 10
A Dendom for Rural Paisers
Thank you, Mary council
G.H., 2Task over 10
We hired them to do the roof projects
Pay plans and specs for five of their
Rough project that we had
That's a heavy Civic Center, library
The pool
And then north in south fire station
At
The South Fire Station on January 6
Fire Chief Ronnie Klein
There was a sag in the roof
So that's on
That is all we moved onto
Looking at this
The Sag had some concerns
We brought into a structural engineer through G.H., 2Task
Immediately because there were concerns
Out of it
It has special rough
A tung and groove system
Which no one knew about
But they had recommendations
Secure it which we have done
So the building secure right now
For that area
The immediate concern
We added is gone
They're working up different roofing options
Four of their rough
To fix this
And so this Dendom
Is giving G.H., 2Task over
To cover the structural component of
The roof and also some additional
Admin part
So,
Check out
Not clear on if this again is to
Release funds for them
Do engineering work or do
These are
Fonsed
They moved ahead because
Of their project they move
They actually go into pay them for those services
So the roof has been repaired
No, this is just
Architecture
Architectural component
The assessment of it
There are working on different options right now
Which also underneath
We would like to point out that
On an interim basis we have taken some steps
To stabilize their roofs
And we have to change it at this point
But a long term effects is not happening yet
We're asking you
To prove the contract
Continue performing work they've already started
I guess i'm just a lower locket that
Approve a large amount of money on
That old building until
You know what
This
If there's
A changing order for
The contract or would have to amend their
Contract this is just the architectural
Component
Contractor before we make any
Go ahead on that they
They'd had a formal change order
To move forward with additional funds
I've
Would like point out
With all these roof projects
We're going
When
We're going to have a lot of
We'll be able
To do this
We will see how we are for the next project
For
The time
We may
We don't
Have any surprises
As long as it's been since these things
We can't guarantee just exactly what we're going to find
Okay
This is part of our budget right now
This one is the budget
So, let's say it has a budget amount
Of money that
That will be able
To have these very few projects
But if
They are all going over
Just based on things
We have to be ready for it
So we need a motion
To approve the agenda
I'll make that
Motion
I'm full of public hearing and
The ordinance
Resoned the property at 505-725815D
St.
Noir
We're planning to implement
Recommended by the Planning Commission
Travis
Council, are you doing this evening?
Good.
I'm currently designing for
The city properties at 505D Northeast
Which is
Current MIME Street Barnet
725D northeast
The city is the public work building
We want to send all those City lots
To, can you give me
Platter
Kind of hard to see
But I've got it in bold
Exhibit A
Lots
8-326
We're going through this on
All that planning development
Which would take into existing structures
As they are
And the proposed animal shelter
The reason I want to do this is
Because
They're proposed plans
Call for a 75-foot front set back
For Animal Shelter
Which required in industrial zoning
We wanted 50 footfront setback
Which would line the animal shelter with
Exhibit building and existing street barn
Plus
With the plan
There's also a future
Future plans for 35 by 30
Addition
So, is it planning to take in this
In addition
To The Animal Shelter
As far as street barn
As if anything
These are things
We got come into the planning commission
Just like the public work
Building if we have an addition
Then will come to a planning commission
For their approval
So as everything sits now
As proposed plan for The Animal Shelter
With that's
That is what this PUDs
Planning and Development
Is on these lots
I'll curious
If you're currently calling for 75 foot setbacks
How do We end up with 50 foot sets?
Supposing, staff going for variants
It's not a hardship
We want to plan the development
Which we're proposing a 50 foot setback
So if anything ever happens
You've got come into The Planning Commission and get approval
Rather than go in with Board of Adjustments
Probably getting turned down
Because that Set Back isn't a hard ship
And I think point out
This was anybody else developing it
This was what we would be asking them to do
So We're following our own rules
Basically, if something ever happens
Say that the public work is building two
And then decide To sell That Building
If somebody wants another brewery
It's like it wasn't before
They wouldn' have come into a planning commission
Because The use of this building has changed
Planning will be based on.
Petsonning is basically roughly equivalent
to planning a piece of roll-off
If you look at regular zoning classifications
You have a cookie cutter and approach
Certain very specific, Cookie Cutters on Inclassification
There's nothing wrong with that
But if people typically wanted To part from That Cookie cuter zone
Classification
As we've discussed in the years past
They would come before The Board of Adjustments
Sometimes called A Bordea Variance
In which they're supposed to establish a hardship
in order To get the variance
Not only for those reasons
But also encourage Read Development
As one of The Wightly Future Growth Eries
For Bringing Forward proposals
That are based on Ord Many Ordnance
Is This City's Hat For Decades
And that is where the Trump Planning and Development
When you do planning A Development
You essentially turn
The parcel of land
Into Think Of It Is Its Own Subdivision
As a plated area
If A Builder in the past came forward
Planning Commission and City Council
And had 40 acres
In one of the Internet of Residents
Supped to Vision that have To Come Forward
This is where this street saw
This was what we used to do.
That arrangement without coming Back
Before the Planning Commission in The City Council
It's not identical but it gets very directly
If you approve this, whether to be for
A city and outside business or even a private residential area
You're basically saying Bring us
Good Plan And we might give you a zoning classification called PED
Which is Not To Cookie Cutter Reproge
But which has customized to not only your circumstances
But our comprehensive Plan and which are Planning Commission
And we as Council think is good for the community
Pointing out of course, that run in a agenda item
It says Public Hearing
So it's some point to Mayor will call
For public comment from The audience
In order may or May not be any
There was none if I recall with planning commission meeting either
Think you'll find that utilizing this legal mechanism
But we'll also afford you a better document
A long term ability to benefit
Community of Read Development
Questions for David?
Or Travis.
Anyone in the audience want To address The issue
Of these properties
Would Planning Commission have any concerns
No, they did not
And it was brought out that
It's Did Go ahead He coincide with our comprehensive
Yes, specifically
Asked Yes
Fakeover on the Board specifically asked that question
Discussed Specifically
Okay, then I'm going to bring The Public Hearing portion
To a close and we're Going
MoveTo Item 13
Which is the ordinance
Reson.
The properties from M2 General
Industrial 2 plan due Development as recommended by
We have a motion.
Most do it for the second
Second.
All.
Item 14
New Business and
15 staff reports
Third in your packet
Marron Council announcements
Yes sir
The bill of
Ream on this separate February 27
From round 4 to back
We have a quick
Part 6.
I think the Chamber of the Firmishing
Refreshments and The Dops & Resumes
Going to Have Exit that's here
So anybody is Welcome To Go
And we're watching Here, I didn't throw Brexit
When it was ready
Okay so
If you are interested in That reunion
It wasn t 27
So please come and see All the exhibits
And other Dops & Resumes
Really need to exist in it
Anything else?
I have 17 citizen manager communications Dean
3 items here on
First, i just want To thank Joe Walgan again
For all of you working did On The Branch
Amp.
And the plaque on
A branch is something that's over do
But some things are good in community
Important
We did receive an extension from FEMA
For a 60 day period of time
You might remember originally when we were
Given these flood maps,
Were asking for 100 and they 120 Day Period
But at that point
That's the way to be doing quite A bit
Of engineering work
In fact it is our last special meeting
To do some Engineering Work with TetraTect
To take a look at this
As it turns out,
FEMA is currently looking At TetraTect Study
They have done It This Point
And in talking with Bob Mustard and Di Thomas about
That they felt that there wasn t
There wasnt to need For them to Really go into Looking
If the Female Report Especially if FEMA Is Looking
So we kind of scaled Back
The Need-To Do The Engineering Work With
Now depending on what happens In
The future there could be a 90 day period of time
By which There would Be A Challenge Of These Maps
And I think At that Time That s
When we might want to use our Budget in relationship
To the Engineering For
So right now We reaTapoint
TryingTo Trade Information with FEMA and FEMA has been Open
Which had Been Very Great for 4
But at THAT point they were Relector
To give us 120 Day Period
They Had No Problem Getting Us Another 60 DAY Period
Now the 60 DAYs Comes After The Original 30 Day
Comment Period So When Everything Is Done
We ll Have a 90 day period of Time To Be able to Do Comments
During This time there are About 3 Things I think we need Consider
First is that
We do Need-ToDo Some Technical Work With FEMA and FEMA
Indecated A Williness
Probably Within about 2 Week s will have a Conference Call
With our People From Tetra Tech Working with their Engineers
Because if you remember the key issue is that we feel
The FEMA Study Is Not Taking Into Account
Through Tetrotek which has really Showed That
Nehoto Shower River System and actually
They re Spring River system. It s much more Dynamic
Where as FEMA Comes In it takes a look at
More As What Bob Mustard Calls A Steady State
Which means You Assume The Lake Levels Always Going To Be Cost
And We ll Be Going By Our Numbers It s Not.
So we want to go into That but also
Sumount Reach To our Partners
We ve Talk Briefly About Trying Have Some Meetings Probably Here At The Civic Center
Where WE Ask A Partner Is To Come In and Try To Share Information With Them
Also going Out & Meeting with some of the partners for example tomorrow
On Schedule 2 MeatWithThe Intertrival Council
To Basically Give Them An Update On What We Know So Far
Check has Been Helping Me Quite A Bit With That with that Information
I think From Here Out a couple of the most important things
Working The Media working and i do want to compliment
News Record They ve Had Really Good Series Of Articles
Highlight At This Problem In Getting People And Vault
We need To Start Working On The Technical aspect of It
And then Try to Get All Over Comments In Within the 60 Day Period
At Time That we ve Got An Extension With A Hope Sofema
Takes a Look Out at and Makes Some Adjustment From There Once They Do
Then Will Know What WE Actually End Up with.
So it s Very Dynamic Program Of This Point
I don t know if there is anything else or any Questions you have for me
Do You The Last Flood In December?
There were a couple of Times A Glendon I Had Calls About Questions
That We Couldn t Answer Because the Dynamic Of The Flooding
And in fact we even had to call GDRDA Couple At times
They Did An Overfly To LoveThe Area
As did you See These Issues that Were Getting Calls Now
DuringThat Time, WE Disgust and Even Had My Emmion
That Got A Dron And Actually Did Some Drone Views Of The Flooding At that Time
Now I want to Go Back About a Year ago
Christ up Had An Inestaph Meeting It s Just We Get A Dron at the City
and i Thought Thats Was The Domest thing Ever heard of
As Tell This Story Several Times
But OverThe Last Years Seeing The Advances On Drone Technology
Going Through Things Like this Flood Will Really Could Have Used A Dron
To Be able to Take A Look At Some Of These Problems That We Have
Other Applications that Are Now Taking Place With Drones
And Then I want a Compliment Glendon Because Through some of the other Flooding
Money thats we had in Assistance From The Federal Government
WE Were AbbleTo Use SomeOfThat money Two By Adron
And With No Further Do I'd Like To Introduce You To Done
to The Drone That We Are Now Reveal Called the Christ up.
This Is THE Christian Christ up?
Made By DJ Axe Inspire Model From All
For K-K camera, X1 came Billy's On
It s Kind Of Flying Pretty Much Find So
You Packed From The Long Shit And Set Way Points That Of Fly To
Way Point As Your Video, you Can Live Fly It Has Two Remotes
So One Person Can Fly On My Personal Can Take Video
to Caffering.
Its a Professional Model and Quality Ground
We re Curringing Getting Used A Little Bit, Testing it
And Writing A Very Extensive Policy.
Yes, I did agree with my owners
There are some Federal Guidelines Of Courseful
We Breast To The FN and Some Other Programs Are But
i think it would be Available to All
One Thing About What We Talk about This First thing
They Get Talking About Was Fourth Amendment Making Sure That
And There Is Not Any Kind Of Enforged But On Anybody's Right of Privacy
By Utilizing This.
So That is why We re Having Such An Extensive Policy and Perseetuous Man You Want
Out These For Your You Know?
I did it!
We anticipate DJI, as we are Leasing a Clear Camera for
It s Full Sponsory Out Napedral
And We Can Use That For Utility Curves.
They s Show The Interest in Hot Spots On Transformers, Lines, Fire Department
Search and Rescue.
Several times we have had people with other People of Wark Drop from One
Nursing Homes
Being To Much to You Find In Then Now
Would Get With Fly & Just Find Hot Sponsory Out
What is the Range Your Trap?
The Range On This One is About Two Minutes.
It s Good They claim almost 10-down feet
I don t know why you ever want Fly That For Our High
But yeah, it's got a Great Range
A Very Life Is Approximately 30 minutes
We bought a kit with And So we had the Storage Box and
Came With Three Batteries for us
With Key Bill, It s Wanting For About Our High
On Diffney B.
Got a Price Tag That.
The Total Package with the Upgrade of Camera
And Battery was 52-54
We did Buy an Upgrade at Kid
DJI Inspire is Right At 28
And How High and You Can Program a Flight
One of the other great aspects Of The Inspire
I re Ever seen Drum Pludgeon YouTube Room here in the middle
Why t s Time To See The Blades, you ll see The Legs
When this takes off to legs Transform
So get Full 360 View
You ll see The Legs, you don t See the Prop s
When it flies or Gives So It's a Full 360 for Professional
Great Millie Quality Pictures
And we have My EpoDag Next.
We Have My EpoDag Next
Yes
Bradding and Being A Valuable Tool
Not just one of Two Place Barman
We ve going to the Tart City
We ve going to Come Up with a Training for Schedule
A Training Program and basically a Pilots Certification Board
Have Three Of Four Guys To Do That
Or Now is that Flood?
And just Use It For Whatever Me, Need Maybe In The City
How does the Weather I mean Is there Another Wax Wind Speed
Is Out A Determined With Certain Wind Speeds
To A Point, Yeah. They say 1015 Up Winds or No Problem
It s Actually Got a GPS Light Mode
So it ll stabilize itself
If you use Let Off Controls
Its Look About Ten Side Lights
And its stay Right Exactly Over Time
if itís Blowing
The GPS Mode In and allows Just to Beats Good Cover
You can Flip Into Operator Mode
You have to Control a Whole Time
And There s A Man Just About Because It s One of this in GPS Mode
Its Holds Up Position So I think i ll Ping Off Side Lights
But the Game Boy on The Camera Holdes Every Solid
Really Good Quality Video
Have you Got a Master?
Pretty Close
That was Solid
This is pretty neat
But we plan to use the attack
On The Third or the Horns Point That For Right
If you go To Video The Prairie
We have Citizens Academy in Progress
Or not says Mind Me You
And I ll Play on the Duelist Footage for that
Among some of their Outdoor Stuff
Well, i want Again